we've got the kks be 13-inch screen
Comperto quod erit XIII-inch screen KKS
stand are you folks ready for this I'm
paratus sum propter hoc stare tu es folks
really excited about this I mean I've
Ego vere excitatur circa hoc quia commune aut inmundum sit
seen 7 inch screens I've seen three and
VII digitis tria screens vidi visum est et mihi
a half inch screens 13 inches
XIII dimidium digiti pollices screens
what okay look at the size of the do you
bene facitis quod inviso magnitudine
see the Raspberry Pi there on the
videre est in RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
left-hand side huh compare that to the
huh conferatur ad sinistra
size of this box okay all right what do
mole huius arca archa, quod bene facere omnia recta
we got here okay we've got some
hic surrexit enim aliquis bene Comperto
instructions this is basic assembly
haec prima lex comitiis
looks pretty simple we'll refer to that
vultus pulchellus simplex ut youll 'relatum ut ut
in just a couple of moments and there it
quemadmodum par rebus ibi
is that's what we get from ksb we've got
ut suus 'quod sit quod ex Catholica Lovaniensis Lovanii Comperto
the stand itself which we're gonna get a
sto ad se amet quam accipere
look at looks nice as always with cake
at wisi semper respicit libo
ASB I'm always impressed with them
Im 'semper cum illis impressa ASB
everything is like a lot of their stuff
quae supellectilem similis multum suae
is made of stainless like of Steel it's
factum est autem ut immaculatus sit suus 'Steel
good solid stuff it's not like a plastic
suus 'non amo a plastic bonum solidum supellectilem
stand that is steel my friends and then
ut ferro resistere et amicis meis epularer
we've got the case itself this is a
Comperto apud se hoc est,
metal case for the Raspberry Pi and of
ad metallum causa et RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
course that would fit any compatible SBC
quod fit quantum quis cursus SBC
like a say an Isuzu tinker board for
dico enim sicut tabula in Isuzu tinker
example if you want a little more power
Ut sis potentiam paulo
we've got a couple of bits in there
Comperto autem ibi duobus bits in
looks like some standoffs and some
et quidam vultus amo standoffs
screws okay so let's get the case out
bene de cochleis sic lets 'adepto in casu,
here Sasha oh right that's all there is
Quis hic Not fas est omnia
to it
ad illud
yeah so let's say let's get a look at
yeah lets 'narro ut lets' adepto per vultus procul
the instructions and see what I actually
et instructiones, et vide quid actually
have to do now first step is I need the
nunc primum gradum facere ad hoc quod opus
actual screen and this skirt this is the
et hoc screen ipsa hac ora est,
butt as the first box I held up here
ludibrium verius quam primum buxum huc sustentavit me
tonight and it's so big that I actually
nocte et factum est ita magnum ut actually
have to clear some space here on the
ut patet in quodam spatio hic a
desk look at the size of that compared
prae magnitudine at elit
to the Raspberry Pi my goodness I'm
RUBUS IDAEUS Pi ad bonitatem mei sum
gonna have to actually clear some space
agnus dei habere aliquid spatii hinc actually
here all right ladies and gentlemen Oh
Quis hic omnia nobilium dominarum
all right there we have it all right
satin habes illic recte
we've got some basic instructions here
Comperto hic aliqua basic instructions
in particular with the Raspberry Pi
maxime cum RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
there are some things that we're gonna
Sunt enim quaedam quae, ut amet
have to add to the config we'll look at
non addere ad te respice in nos aboutconfig
that in just a couple of minutes but
iustus autem in duobus minutis
hold on to that we've got a power supply
ut teneat potestatem habeo copiam
got a barrel connector there and
atque inde surrexit dolium iungo
there you go twelve volts thousand
duodecim milia Grat erating
milliamps nice okay set that aside we've
set quod bene deponere ut Ive 'nice quod milliamps
got a USB cable this is actually believe
possedi USB cable in actu, hoc est credere
it or not this is also a touchscreen so
quod hoc sit vel non ita touchscreen
we're gonna need that USB cable to
qui sumus agnus dei opus USB cable
operate the the touch and we've got a
Comperto autem quod in tactu, et agunt
nice little short HDMI cable to connect
parum grata ad coniungere brevi HDMI cable
the PI end we've got a universal
Comperto autem quod ex prima hujus finis universae
connector just in case you're not here
sicut si non hic te COPULATOR
in Canada or the u.s. there is the
in Canada, illic sit et in nobis:
screen look at that Wow okay so think
Curabitur ut elit at purus putant
about this for a second this is a
de hoc in hoc secunda
Raspberry Pi three case / screen we've
Si tria RUBUS IDAEUS Pi / screen eget
got the connectors on the back to
obtinuit ut connexiones in
actually mount it to 13.3 inch and for
13.3 inch enim mons est in actu,
those of you wondering this is 1080p
qui ex vobis est admiratio 1080p
it's got a film there which we're going
sit amet suus 'got ibi, quae erant' iens
to remove in just a couple of moments
duo momenta prorsus tollere
what we'll leave it on there for a
ea quae ibi relinquam
moment just a protective film yeah well
tunc iustus a tutela yeah bene amet
alright then on its face mmm-hmm okay so
Licuit ergo vultum suum super-kk et bene hmm
step one let's see here we've got to put
unus step videamus Hic weve 'got ad induendum
these little plastic little risers on to
scamilli ad modicum pusillis dignissim
the back of the screen here so dig
huc elit tergo dig
through our trusty little bag of goodies
fidissimis per saccellum lacus
there we are one and two some exciting
ibi sunt unum et duo quaedam excitando
TV right there yeah yeah through the
Yeah recta TV est per yeah
magic of television I can speed things
omnia possum velocitatem A televisionem et magia
up which is a beautiful thing for those
nam quas pulchrum esse
of you watching at home alright what
vigilantes vestrum domi quid licet
else have I got
aliud est mihi,
okay so step two let's see what's next
duo gradus ut bene videamus quid suus 'postero
alright we've got that we've got the kit
Comperto autem quod licet Comperto ornamentum
the stand need to put that here and I'm
sto ad opus est ut hic et posuit me
actually going to need to screw the case
actu iens ut postulo causam screw
into the stand so I'm gonna need these
amet in me sto et his indigetis
little metal risers everything's just
sicut est omne metallum minus surgunt
pictures for the instructions but I
sed per instructiones imaginibus
guess the visual of the video tonight
coniecto per visual de nocte video
will help as well then I'm gonna put
Bene ergo ego auxiliatus sum ut Im 'agnus dei implebis
some these screws in here if I can get
hos aliquis, si possumus hic irrumet ipsum
all of them
omnium eorum
there's one and where the other one go
Ubi illic 'unus et alter ad alterum
oh there it is on my screwdriver okay so
O bene est ut solus sit a me
now flip this over and we're gonna put
et nunc hic sumus agnus dei flip implebis
these metal little riser type washers on
in riser washers generis metallum illa paulo
there they're a little thicker than the
non es autem paulo densior est, quam
standard washer and now put that on to
washer autem posuit vexillum et in illo die
the underside of the stand so this is
tanta est in hoc corpore subtus
not gonna go on the face side keep in
agnus dei ire in faciem servet
mind the monitor is gonna go on that
quod mens sit amet monitor vade in illo
side but just like that a couple of
sed usque ut duo
couple of nuts to hold it on there we go
Non tenuit duo pergerent Nuces
we can speed things up for you yeah get
nos volo impetro res sursum pro vobis yeah
those tightened up nothing too difficult
qui nihil difficilius constringantur
here Sasha hmm so very easy peasy as
Hmm Peasy quod tam facilis hic Not
simple as that and that's the cake ASB
id quod simplex est et crustulam ASB
design and and they make some fantastic
Suspendisse aliquam consilio faciunt
high-end stands so if you're looking at
Si summus finem et stat ad vos quaeritis
cake ASB versus competition keep in mind
crustulam ASB versus competition in mente custodi
what you're seeing here today this is a
quod petis hic cum hodie hoc est,
nice steel stand and we're gonna pop
Nice pop ferro sto et amet
that raspberry pie in there now that
quod est amet nunc, qui pie in
we've got that mounted on the back it's
Comperto quod in tergo est mounted
just gonna just slide right in there as
sicut agnus dei sicut non sunt infirmata est in dextera
is the case with cake ASB everything is
est causa quae est per placenta ASB
perfectly molded and ready to go and now
perfecte formata et nunc parati
I need I've I need some little risers
Ego sum paulo opus est postulo per scamillos
here these don't look like the ones
hic sunt non ut
though these are a little bit too thick
quae quamquam exigua sunt nimis densissima
yeah they definitely that's not the one
non memini quod ille certo
that's gonna fit in there so looking at
quod suus 'agnus dei apta est igitur in tempore vultus
my bag of tricks hmm what else have I
quid aliud mihi peram dolis ego hmm
got here let's see that's not gonna work
non est hic surrexit lets 'animadverto ut suus' agnus dei opus
mmm not gonna just screw it directly and
sicut agnus, et non directe illud screw mmm
I need to have some kind of standoffs
Opus ad quaedam standoffs
there aha bag number two these ones look
Vah qui peram et videte numerum illorum
a little more promising yes much finer
Etiam paulo plus spei multo honestiores
look at that okay so get the Raspberry
aspice ut bene ut in RUBUS IDAEUS
Pi in there now according to the
In pi iam non secundum
instructions I just need to put these
ego iustus opus ad induendum huiusmodi instructiones
standoffs in the bottom
In fundo standoffs
right here and while speed this up just
Dumque hoc modo hic celeritatem
because you know screwing the sin by
nescitis quoniam qui peccatum in futuit
hand is not all that exciting for you to
non enim te manum tuam omnia quae excitando
watch there you go
tu vigilias
no tools needed I guess I well I
EGO coniecto EGO sum opus instrumenta nec bene
shouldn't say that
Non debet dicere
I do need a Phillips screwdriver to
Opus operor ego solus, ut Tullius
screw in the final screws but a lot of
screw in ultima Cochleas, sed multum
this stuff is just done by hand
ista iusta manufacta
there you go let's get that in there
lets 'adepto vos non est in illo
nice and tight nice and snug for those
stricta et grata ea pro terra fovere et delicatus
of you looking for the screen they are
screen vultus pro vos sunt
at cap five dot TV slash PI and there
c TV quinque ad apicem hujus et ibi VULNUS
you go so those two standoffs are
ita et tu duo standoffs
holding the Raspberry Pi three in place
tenentem de tribus in locis RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
and now I'm just gonna snap this on here
Im 'agnus dei sicut hic et nunc super haec disrumpam
k KS B cases are traditionally very well
OK k casibus B sunt traditionally nimis
fitted and everything's just gonna snap
et iusta omnia aptavit suus 'agnus dei frangeretur
together if yes there you go snap it in
Etiam si tu non simul in disrumpam
there perfect and you can just feel it
non est perfectus iustus et sentiunt
go right into its place and everything
et omnia recta in
is all well aligned they're so eager ab
Immo adeo ab rectene amet
a--
a--
in discord its cap 5tb /pi to see any of
5TB discordiae ejus in cap / pi ut aliquo
the raspberry pi peripherals that we
RUBUS IDAEUS ad pi ut peripherals
review here on category five TV and of
Hic genus in TV et quinque review
course this case and the screen is is
Nempe hoc est quod tentorium
there as well if you're watching live it
quod est bene vivere, nisi quia vos vigilo
will take about 24 hours before you'll
tollet de XXIV horas ante te ibo
see that there now I'm just lining up
videamus nunc, Im 'iustus non enascentia
these long screws do you see that
haec quae videtis diu Cochleas
through the air vent I just got to kind
quodam modo habere apertum aerem
of make sure that gets through the hole
et fac quod gets per foraminis
and screw that in with this allen key
et screw in hoc key Allen
that has been provided to easy this is
quod est facile ad hoc est provisum
perfect perfect indeed Sasha I could do
perfecta perfecta quidem facere potui, Sasha
this with one hand tied behind my back
hoc est autem post tergum meum manum ligatum
there we go
ibi imus
this would make a fantastic kiosk I
haec faciunt ut fantastic ac ante te
gotta say yeah
Redditus est nobis dicere yeah
I gotta put these back on cuz I've
Gotta posuit super me horum cuz quia commune aut inmundum
knocked them off I don't know why that
ambos eam nescio quare
was step one it could have been whatever
unum gradum et quicquid potuit
this is now there we go okay so now line
hoc modo aciem purus nunc vadimus
all those up
in omnibus his
with the screw holes for the back plate
in dorso domibus argentum stupra
there and we're gonna put this all
ibi posuit et nos haec omnia amet
together there you go so this is just
ita iustus fueris ibi
gonna mount right onto the back of that
ascendit super dorsum esse jus amet
13.3 inch screen remember this is 1080p
13.3 inch screen est meminisse 1080p
folks I want to check these risers that
quae fit per scamillos volui inhibere
are that's our seemingly extra they
videtur quod sint extra nos sunt,
don't seem to be for anything I'm not
Non enim videtur esse aliquid non sum
sure what they're for maybe I could I
certus quod tu ad me maybe non poterat
could elevate those plastic pieces but
sed elevet eas partes esse plasticae
it doesn't seem necessary so I won't use
non videtur necessarium ut non utor
them today cuz the extra bits it's like
Hodie suus 'similis cuz illos qui extra bits
when you buy something from Ikea and
Cum emere aliquid a et Ikea
you've got a couple of extra screws left
possedi duobus relicto extra te Cochleas
over you know what they're just a bonus
super te dicere quam iustus a bonus
bonus bonus bits there you go 16k you
16k bits est bonus bonus es tu
think do you do do you there uber ABBA
existimo enim quod non sunt uber es ABBA
I know this is 1080p realistically sony
Scio hoc sensu realitatis Sony 1080p
has been working on some attending some
has been opus in quodam pars in ministerio
16k technology but it's gonna be a while
16k technology tamen suus 'agnus dei esse a dum
before we see it on a Raspberry Pi case
prius videamus hoc RUBUS IDAEUS Pi in casu,
alright a quick side step from the live
licet gradus parte a velox vivet
show because after the show
palam ostendit, quia post
I've noticed that the screws here that
Ive 'animadverto ut hic, quod cochleis
are holding the case like the stand
sunt sicut sto apud tenens
itself to the monitor are actually
in se etiam monitor
touching the back of the screen and so I
ideoque de dorso elit
realized I think that might be what
intellexit quod esset puto
these extra standoffs are for so for the
Hi sunt extra standoffs nam ut ad
sake of accuracy and just because you
et quod iusta causa accuratae rerum narrationi officiat
may want to do this right the first time
ut primum hoc ius vis ut faciam tibi
let's give that a try
dare operam scriptor
and again I've sped this up just for the
Et iterum: Ego autem sicut ad id tendit
sake of good TV
causa boni TV
I don't know that these standoffs are
Nescio quod haec sint standoffs
going to make like it doesn't look like
non quasi simile facturum
it's causing any damage on the back of
suus dampnum facientem in posteriore
the screen but I figure hey if that's
sed si instar heus in screen ut '
what the manufacturer has included them
quod includitur in illa quae corporis fabrica
for then we definitely want to use them
et tum certus volo utor eos
now okay so the reason that these didn't
Bene autem quod non est ex
fit when I was doing this live is
quod fit cum hoc vivunt
because I had the plastic washers on the
quod habuit in plastic washers
other side of these it looks like this
Contra hoc autem videtur
actually goes the other way around so
Sequitur ergo e converso ipsum
it's like maybe you can use a standoff
sicut maybe suus 'uti potes dirigebant
or a washer but this is definitely going
sed hoc est certus non a washer
to solve the fact that it's touching the
solvere de hoc quod suus '
screw is touching the screen and they do
stupra enim ad screen et non faciunt
fit as long as you don't have the washer
dum non fit fullonibus
there so I think just step one was not
iustum est, ut arbitror, non esset una step
very clear in the picture you couldn't
non posset manifeste in tabula
see those standoffs under the plastic so
plastic vident illa ita in standoffs
I think step one is actually showing
Ego autem gradus est effective demonstraretur
these standoffs with those plastic
Haec cum plastic standoffs
washers on top but of course in the
Sed volutpat cursus desuper
picture you can only see this the
te potest solum in hoc picture
plastic washers you can't actually see
cernere oculis non potes plastic washers
the standoffs just like right now so now
nunc ergo sicut et in standoffs
you have it
quia habetis
[Music]
[Musica]
all right there we go there's the
Ibi omnis dextera est illuc imus,
difference so again I don't know that
differentiam etiam nesciunt
the screws going directly into this was
Erat autem in cochleis pervenientes
going to cause any issue the standoffs
et semen facturus standoffs
are also very very close to touching the
De ipso etiam proximus
back of the monitor I think it just
revertere ad monitor puto tantum
avoids screwing into the the monitor
vitat ad monitor in futuit
itself accidentally pushing on the back
accidentaliter se ulteriora dorsi
and now let's pick it up where we left
Nunc lets 'quo colligunt, et relinquentes eam
off all right let's grab that short
omni iure capto scriptor brevis
little HDMI cable and plug that into the
Parum est ut plug funem theatre
Raspberry Pi there you go and it's going
Ibi suus 'iens vos et RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
to come around the side check this out
ad reprehendo parte ista circa
we've got all these inputs on the side
Comperto parte ista inputs
here we've got HDMI I see well let's
Comperto HDMI hic video etiam lets '
let's get a better look here so straight
lets 'adepto a melius vultus recta, ut hic,
into the HDMI there for the for the
in theatre non est enim
Raspberry Pi but we've also got HP I'm
Tamen weve 'quoque got me RUBUS IDAEUS Pi HP
not sure that looks like an audio
Non certus ut vultus amo an audio
adapter VGA HDMI touch and DC so the DC
L. nibh ut tactum dc VGA theatre
adapter we know is provided but we want
scimus enim nibh nulla re indigemus nisi provisum
to connect that touch as well I'm
id quoque tactu coniungere me
actually a little pleasantly surprised
parum etiam iucunde mirari
if you will a little shocked that this
hoc parum sis meque
has multi-touch built-in because it's
has built multi-tactus-in quod suus '
you know you're just expecting a really
quia tu es vere iustus expectans
nice little screen but to have that
sed paulatim tincidunt elit habere
multi-touch as well so touch just means
sicut tactum est multi- tangimus tantum
that you wouldn't need a keyboard at all
ut non opus est omnino a cappella
we don't need a mouse and I suppose if
mus et, si opus non putant
you wanted to you could use an on-screen
Vos could utor an on-screen ad te voluit
keyboard but for kiosk or just for
sed tincidunt vel ac ante in justo
general use if you want to put L cars on
communis usus cars on Si Vis posuit Dominus
there then there you go but doesn't that
Ibi ergo sunt, sed non quod tu
look beautiful just stunning so you've
Suspendisse ut youve 'iustus vultus pulchra
got a couple cables sticking out of the
got a duobus funibus marinis ab his excusi pulli
side there but that's nothing to be
sed nihil ad latus
concerned about I mean it looks really
is vultus vere sum sollicitus sit
good really clean and the final thing
bonum vero purum et supremum est
the final thing
extremum illud
ashle yes the final thing as I shimmy on
Etiam illud quod supremum in ashle Shimmy
over here the final thing that we need
hic enim est opus in extremum
to do is configure this to work with the
hoc facere est operari cum configurare
screen so you noticed on the
animadvertit in screen sic vos
instructions that I pulled out of the
instructiones quod de extraxerunt
box there there were there was a little
ibi erat arca archa erant paulo
bit of information about what I need to
aliquantulus of notitia circa quae necessaria sunt
do a little extra for Raspberry Pi I
et paulo extra te in RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
mentioned that it has multi-touch so
quod aliquando est tanta multi-tactus
keep in mind that I believe for
Credo enim quod in cordibus suis
Raspberry Pi it's single touch but if
Si unum uerum illud Ps amet
you have it connected to a computer say
dico autem vobis iunctus ut a computer
a Windows 10
X in Fenestra
machine or something like that then
aut sicut aliquid, quod tunc machina
you've got multi-touch as well okay so
tu quoque surrexit ut bene multi-tactus est
it's it's not just a Raspberry Pi screen
suus 'suus' non iustus a screen RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
you can connect this to other devices as
vos can coniungere cum hoc alias machinas
well but of course with the ksb
sed tum scilicet cum Lovaniensis
components it's it's like the perfect
components ut suus 'suus' perfectus
raspberry PI's system so I just want to
RUBUS IDAEUS Pi ratio est ut iustus volo
bring it up on my screen here I've got
Ego got is sursum in meus screen hic adducere
the the SD card plugged into my laptop
SD card plugged in a laptop
and with that alright on Windows 10 I
et quia non licet in Fenestra X
can see the config dot txt file so with
non potest videre apicem aboutconfig file sic txt
this I want to just scroll right to the
hoc solum volo ius ad librum
end of this file and add those lines I'm
huius terminus file: et adde eas lineas me
just going to type those right in then
iustus iens ut typus eorum et rectum est in
we'll call this the beautiful KK SB 13
Hanc nos speciosa KK XIII SB
inch screen case from cat 5 TV slash PI
inch screen TV V casu cattus ex prima hujus VULNUS
so I have no idea what these things do
ita quoque nescio quid
it's just I'm following the directions
suus 'iustus ego et sequenti directiones
I'm doing what I'm told
Ego sum facis, quod me dixi
Mac's USB current equals one HDMI group
Mac scriptor current USB pares unum coetus HDMI
equals two HDMI mode equals 82 HDMI CVT
LXXXII modus HDMI dividuntur, duo efficiuntur pares HDMI Navi
1920 1080 66000 I presume that means
MCMXX MLXXX (LXVI) minime puto,
1080p 60 frames per second and there we
LX tabulae erunt per secundus, et ibi 1080p
go so it'll take a split second to boot
alterum Fabio ducam eam tam scissura
that thing up once it's up will be will
illud autem est illud statim vult esse
be back and will actually show you what
ut ostenderet tibi quod et te ipsum
this system looks like on screen this is
Haec ratio est in screen vultus amo
the K KSP 13.3 inch Raspberry Pi case
13.3 inch KSP in K si RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
screen multi-touch screen it's it's
Multi- tactus screen est scriptor tentorium
super cool beautiful I can't wait to put
frigus ut eximius expectare possim decora
this up we'll see it after this quick
Id quidem facile videbit nos
little break cigarette
paulo confractus cigarette
[Music]
[Musica]
for a limited time get your hands on
in stricto vicis impetro vestri manus super
limited-edition shirts from the category
Genus-Shirt limitata editions
5 TV network these high quality shirts
V TV network qualis haec altus-shirts
are manufactured by teespring
fabricari per teespring
a fundraising website and your purchase
a fundraising vestri website et emptio
will help support the shows we produce
support auxiliatus est nobis ostendit producendum
get yours today and send us your
ut tibi hodie tuam et mitte nobiscum
pictures to be featured on the
ut featured in imaginibus
corresponding show visit cap 5 dot TV
respondens V cap dat TV ostende visita
slash shirts to support us and get your
exacuere vade ad sindones, nos adepto vestri
official Network shirt today cap five
Network publica shirt quinque hodie c
dot TV slash shirts
shirts dat TV VULNUS
[Music]
[Musica]
welcome back this is category five
genus hoc recipiet quinque
technology TV and we are looking at the
technology in TV et nos spectamus
kick-ass B 13.3 inch Raspberry Pi
Asinus calce abjecistis B 13.3 inches-RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
multi-touch screen case somebody was
si quis autem multi-tactus screen
saying in - yeah Marsh man said those
dicens per - Marsh yeah hominem qui dixit:
numbers will set resolution and
Numbers ponam senatus
over/under scan so in the image fits
super / sub scan est in imagine; utiq;
over and under scan so if you've got
Si scan in te surrexit ergo et
like a border around the screen for
quasi tentorium circa marginem
example then you can adjust that okay
bene igitur exemplum, quod vos can adjust
okay
bene
in this case I guess because of the
in hoc casu, ego coniecto propter
instructions saying zero zero zero then
dixit ergo nulla nulla nullus instructiones
you don't have I guess maybe no overscan
EGO coniecto maybe vos non habent nec overscan
mm-hmm
hmm mm,
let's find out should we get read over
ne fiat nobis et scitote et videte per get read
to it yeah
ad eam yeah
find the button and there we go Beauty
Et itur forma non invenire button
Tom I touch the screen and that came to
Tom me tangere screen, et factum est in
life yay Sasha do you want to walk over
Yay vitae Sasha volunt ambulare faciam super vobis
there and and you can actually well
ac ibi bene potest esse et
Vanna White this sash is gonna just jump
Alba Vanna salire sicut lumbare istud est agnus
right over there and and BR our Vanna
Ibi ius nostrum Vanna BR
okay so first of all we've got some kind
ut primum aliqua purus Comperto
of rippling going on do you want to peel
fragoribus avocet agatur vis ut excorio
off the now okay I want to just say this
nunc bene off iustus volo dicere id
is not a Samsung Galaxy fold so it's a
non ut suus 'a grege Samsung VIA LACTEA
yeah it's safe to peel off the polymer
yeah suus 'tutum est polymer decoriabit albugines
let's take a look around so this is so
lets 'vultus circuitu et accipies ita
thirteen point three inches how can we
Quo uero hoc loco tredecim tres pollices
let give you some kind of what that's
quam dare quod sit aliquid
not really a good I've nothing but a
non vere bonam sed Nil
self a smartphone does that help a big
a Mauris quis felis enim se esse a magnus auxilium
smart phone that's a pretty big
dolor phone quod est a pulchellus magnus
smartphone this is the the f1 the poco
Mauris quis autem est iste de F1 poco
phone f1 so you know comparison wise
et tu scis phone F1 collatio sapientes
hand there's your hand okay so how is
quomodo tam bene suus 'vestri manus manus sunt
the touch Sasha because we haven't had
quia neque tactum Not
to do and I know that they can't really
et faciatis scire eos quia non est realiter
see you can I play around a little bit I
Ego ludere circa et vos can animadverto exigua,
think it would be best if you do oh we
Quis enim te puto esse optimum
haven't done any calibration all we've
Weve omnes calibratiis nec aliquid
done is booted up raspbian and this is
profuerit ad hoc agendum raspbian
just raspbian linux re games can you go
Linux raspbian ludos potest iusta de re ad te
to games yeah Python games I don't know
yeah Pythone ad ludos ludos nescio
I don't know this is just a vanilla wow
Nescio quo autem modo in vanilla buy vilis LATRO
that's a really fun game the guys
quod suus 'a fun ludo in guys realiter
what's the game I'm looking and it looks
Quid ludum spectat et in me?
like it's I mean that's a really fine
sicut est vere id quod suus 'non vult bene
fine resolution there you go but I
sed non tu denique senatus
opened a game oh there you go
aperuit quis arcu ingredientur illuc
here we go she's like yeah I did it by
Nunc ad ea quae suus per simile yeah sum
accident but it works Oh how's that how
Quam vero id quod accidit operatur
is the calibration so it's working it's
calibration est ut suus operatus est
good so when you touch stuff is it yeah
memini enim quando bene contingit circium
oh I heard something
audivi quod utinam
oh yeah it's making some noises so the
O Yeah alicuius sonitus sic suus
screen also has built-in speakers coming
et has constructum- in screen venit loquentium
off the HDMI you guys hear that from my
off in theatre audiam de vobis guys
mic you'd hear it more if I was if I was
Si youd potius non essem, si te audierit microform me
playing five minutes - a winner there we
ludens quinque minuta - a victor ibi
go very nice okay what else can you do
ire potes quid pulchrum purus
so this this is raspy Inanna
et hoc est Manuel de vocalibus hiulca
on the KSP 13-inch screen okay so let's
XIII-inch screen bene in KSP sic lets '
see we have office so LibreOffice yeah
yeah officium habent et non videbunt LibreOffice
let's see let's try and open one of
videamus ne unus experiri aperire
these this is great dude there's a
hisce enim magna ibi Dudus
keyboard at your feet if you care to
Si velis tincidunt pedum tuorum
grab a keyboard and then let's just
capto a cappella et lets 'iustus
there yes unplug it you can I was just
et quod sic non potes me modo unplug
on the charger that's why it's at your
ideo in disco ad eam
feet ah there's a power switch right
ah pedes illic 'a dextris virtutem switch
there okay is it is it already oh yeah
O bene est, ibi est prius yeah
look at that
aspice
so is it so that's quick yeah just move
ita quod movetur ita velociter sicut Yeah
your keyboard down so that we get the
usque ad adepto ut vestri keyboard
screen and focus there there we go
screen et non esse itur focus
so touch wise good everything works like
ut omnia bona opera ita contingit sapienti
a by touch here yeah oh yeah this is
O Yeah memini hic est in tactu
great
magna
I want this no don't Wow
Nec hoc volo facio Wow
do you see the house that was like a
vides autem erat quasi domus
little time regardless of the speed of
temporis ratione velocitatis
the Raspberry Pi 3 the fact that she was
quod erat in III RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
able to touch that little X in the top
X parum possunt tangere quæ ad summitatem
right and we didn't have to do any
et jus non habent ullam facere
calibration yeah that is astonishing
calibration yeah, quod est mirabile
ultra intuitive Wow
Wow ultra intuitive
I love this size-wise Sasha how does it
-Amo hac mole quid agit sapiens sit, Sasha
feel feels great can we like how can I
Quo uero non possumus magnus sentit amo sentiunt
like if I had a laptop or like I could
Similiter autem si velim et possim velit
pull my laptop out and show you size
laptop trahendum meam, et ostendam tibi ex magnitudine
comparison wise yeah does that help at
yeah collatio fit sapiens, qui ad auxilium,
all like this is approximately a little
parum placebat fere
bit smaller than my laptop screen which
meus laptop screen quod est aliquantulus minor
is covered in dust this is the perfect
perfectum est puluerulentus operitur
size really oh I don't want to do
O vere amplitudo Non vis ut faciam tibi
shutdown hex get out of there I wasn't
shutdown omnis hexagonis traversa adepto ex ibi erat
watching what did he do yeah yes just
sic vigilabo quid fecit sicut yeah
pressing buttons or some buttons what I
Bullae vel aliquid quod urgeat Bullae
do best
facere optimum
Internet chromium web browser or that's
Internet pasco textus interdum vel ut '
not what I picked
non quae lecta
I picked claws mail cancel okay Internet
Mail bene irritum Internet sum virorum electorum atque unguibus aureis
Oh sometimes if you hit it with your
O si aliquando ledo eam cum vestris
knuckle it doesn't work so this is in
talo non opus est ut hic
full resolution 1080p I might even want
Resolutio nolumus ut 1080p
to put in like 720p just to make it just
Simili modo ut ad iustitiam 720p
so that it's not so tiny em hmm but so
ut suus 'non minima em tam verum hmm
if you go to like I mean this is just
Si libet ad hoc ut sit iustus est
web browser on on raspbian no big deal
non est magnus paciscor in pasco telam in raspbian
but so there you have it I mean there's
nisi ita sit et quod non habes illic '
the KSP case
causa est KSP
can we just I'm gonna if you want to
EGO iustus volo ut Im 'agnus dei, si possumus,
come back around Sasha I'm just gonna
Non sum, 'agnus dei circa reversus Sasha
bring this back up and let's actually
huius bring up et reversus est in actu,
get a look at it as far as how this
ad ea vultus pro a quo usque hunc
looks
oculorum
there you go so this is a little bit of
hoc est ut vos paulum ab
a you know a different view for you but
scitis autem quia per aliud
that's just absolutely awesome and
id omnino iustum et horribilis
there's the Raspberry Pi sitting on the
est ibi sedebat super RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
back nice and solid and you saw Sasha
rursus solidum delicatus et vidi et Sasha
they're kind of operating things for us
erant autem quidam operating pro nobis
I think just right there is the perfect
Puto enim iustum est perfectus
spot for it if I don't knock everything
quae si non evertere locum
over so the KSP 13.3 inch Raspberry Pi
ita in digitis IDAEUS Pi KSP 13,3
screen case is available at cat5 TV /pi
si is available at CAT5 screen TV / pi
now these are brand new
Hi sunt autem novam
and so stock is like is coming about
et venit de stirpe similis
we're starting to see it in America and
et erant incipiens videre in Americae
it certainly it's available
illud certe suus 'available
internationally as well through their
etiam per eorum internationally
website you can get to their website by
ut ad eorum website vos potest a website
going to our website category five dot
dat euntibus nobis quinque Category
TV clicking on support the show and then
Tum TV spectaculum clicking in support
you'll see partner links and in the
et in youll 'animadverto socium Links
partner links you'll see ksb both
socium Links youll 'animadverto utrumque Catholica Lovaniensis Lovanii
international and US but just a quick
sed sicut a velox quod US gentium
way to find this particular device this
ita ut id quod maxime fabrica
ring the screen and the case it's
et si suus 'in screen tinniant
available at cap five dot TV slash PI
c praesto quinque ad apicem hujus TV VULNUS
I'm really really excited about this
Im 'vere excitatur circa hanc rem
because like there's never really been
quia sicut ibi est suus 'non realiter
this kind of kiosk case ready and
paratus sit hoc Kiosk
available to the consumer market you see
praesto sunt, perussi forum vides
them sometimes like in in businesses and
in negotiis interdum simile
things and you know that they pay so
ut sciatis et pretium
much for those things but this is the
sed quantum ad ea quae sunt ad hoc
perfect little kiosk for like sitting at
nam minus perfectum ac ante sedebat quasi
your front desk or even just for your
fronte desk pro vestra aut etiam iustus
personal use for your kitchen counter
contra usum personalem vestra culina
holy cow yeah you imagine recipes it
vitula eligans yeah sanctus es recipes ut meditati
could help me cook oh my gosh this is
non coques o mihi me hoc est gosh
perfect
perfectus
next step is I got an experiment with
Ego obtinuit ad non gradum proximum progredi an experimentum
the on-screen keyboard getting that
in questus in-screen ut tincidunt
configured because I knew that would be
set quia ego cognovi quod non esset,
the next the next best thing is actually
altera in altera esse actu optimum
using the on-screen keyboard to be able
in-screen usura a tincidunt ad poteris
to control it yes it's a full Linux
Ad illud quod sic suus 'a control plena Linux
computer it's not a tablet you're not
suus 'non es computatrum non Tablet
limited to like iOS or something like
terminata sunt, aut aliquid amo ut iOS
that right this is a full debian-based
qui pleno jure est quod, secundum debian
computer so whether it be internet
computatrum num ita sit penitus
surfing or installing apps or whatever
sive superficies vel inaugurari Apps
you want to do it's all available to you
vis ut faciam tibi praesto est omnibus
it's raspbian it is just a Raspberry Pi
raspbian sit suus 'iustus a RUBUS IDAEUS Pi
three sitting on the back of it so could
tres sedens a tergo possit, ut ex eo
you put retropie on that and then like
sicut et vos eadem retropie
yes play I it would be extreme overkill
Et quod sic ludere overkill hoc maxime esset,
in some ways because you wouldn't really
quia non vere esset in aliquo vias
have a use for the touchscreen but you
sed habent usum propter touchscreen
could do it and it would become like a
et facti sunt quasi non posset facere
portable screen man your retropie
virum vestri portable screen retropie
although that's it I kind of laugh about
quod cum ipso genere lactitiast
that suggestion because you know
id quod scis suggestion
retropie on a touchscreen is overkill
retropie in touchscreen est overkill
but remember retropie raspbian all the
sed memento omnium retropie raspbian
different distros that you can put on a
alia quae effingere distros
Raspberry Pi are on an SD card right so
SD card sunt Pi justum amet
you can safely shut it down pull the SD
extrahere poteris eam clausum SD
card for raspy
card pro vocalibus hiulca
put in your gaming card for retropie
gaming pro vobis in card retropie
beat it up use it for gaming right and
gaming pro iure uti, et beat eum
then unplug that and plug back in the
et tunc plug unplug eo retro
other one and you can just keep swapping
unum et alterum ut vos can iustus permutando
back and forth whatever you want to do
Quidquid vis illuc
so if you want to take it to the cottage
Si velis ad casam
and use that as a screen for watching
vigilantes in ea in screen, et uti,
movies and playing video games you can
ludens video ludos movies quod vos can
and then when you bring it home you can
potes domum revocatis deinde
put it back into recipe mode for the
posuit enim in modum facito
kitchen right how cool is that
Quam frigidus est, quod rectum culina
I love it cat 5 TV /pi to pick one of
Quia amo feles TV V / pi ut elige unum
those up
in ea
[Music]
[Musica]
[Applause]
[Plausus]